3645 Welbourn Road

Apt 434 Bryan, TX

Sean Daniel Davis
s.davis@tamu.edu
214-799-7708
No Current Clearance

Texas A&M University 400 Bizzell St College Station, TX

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

After graduating, I desire to elevate my skills and serve within my country, creating and maintaining a safer cyber space. Traveling and meeting new people are things I value most in a job. I am driven to accomplish my goals and strive to surpass people's expectations of me. My favorite job experience has been teaching people and helping to solve practical problems within my community.

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University (3.825)

Computer Science, m. Cyber Security

College Station, TX
05/2023

Stephen F. Austin High School (3.76)

Graduated Summa Cum Laude

Sugarland, TX
05/2019

Top 10% of graduating class with honors

COURSEWORK

- Analysis of Algorithms (C++)
- Computer Systems
- Programming Studio (Python, CSS, JS, HTML, PHP, MySQL)
- Data Structures (C++)

- Discrete Structures and Mathematics
- Programming Languages (Scheme, Java)
- Computer Organization(HDL,ASM)

SKILL SET

Technical Skills

• C++

- CSS
- JavaScript
- HTML

- React JS
- Linux/UNIX

• Python **Professional Skills**

Java

- Team Management, Teaching, and Interpersonal Communication
- Debugging and Troubleshooting and Code Review

EXPERIENCE

Telemundo Houston | KTMD Dec 2020 – January 2021

Computer Engineer / IT Intern 40 hours

- Analyzed the anatomy of a cyber-attack and defense in the field of TV broadcast
- Maintain servers and software for news broadcast, including systems used by 40 instation editors and managers (Unity, Stratus editing, KVM, Dejero encode/decode)
- Learned life cycle of an IP address in computer networking and broadcast
- Maintained and deployed new technology to associates including cellular phones, laptops, TV station cameras, video encoding boxes

Texas A&M University July 2020 – Present

Teaching Assistant for Discrete Structures 10 hours

- Taught and assisted engineering students through one on one sessions to understand Discrete Structure and Analysis of algorithms
- Developed a higher level of understanding of analysis of algorithms through peer teaching

Home Depot April 2020 – August 2020

Deliveries Associate

- Prepared and delivered 10 deliveries of lumber and concrete onto delivery trucks from the warehouse every day
- Interacted with and grew personable skills with customers in customer service center

KEY PROJECTS

TV Station Equipment Upgrade – Telemundo Inc.

- Installed chipsets into all new station cameras allowing them to store video and be used by emergency first responders for quicker broadcast
- Deployed new phones, connecting 28 field reporters to the corporate network, equipped with faster data chips and more reliable internet connection for emergency broadcasts

Sneeze – *Texas A&M Game Developers*

• Worked with 2 other developers to fully deploy a small video game called "Sneeze" from start to finish. *Responsibilities*: movement mechanics, path tracking and AI movement.

A/V Installation – Brian Consolidated

- Installed and tested 3 sound systems for different high school graduation ceremonies
- Ran live sound at event and learned audio mixing and effects

ACTIVITIES AND HONORS

Engineering Team Lead – Intro to Engineering 2019

- Served as a project lead for a Python based video game with 4 developers
- Developed a video game closely resembling popular Japanese RPG "Pokémon"

Project Member – Aggie Coding Club 2020

• Contributed research and brainstorming for a project to build a custom voxel engine before COVID-19 ended the project.

Drum Major – Austin High School Band 2019

- Represented a band of 140 students at national conferences and competitions
- Taught students' intricate styles of marching and formations, as well as directing musical compositions

REFERENCES

Philip Muller – Supervising Manager at KTMD Telemundo Houston

• (281)-684-8678

Melanio Polanco – Co-worker at KTMD Telemundo Houston

• (832)-306-8821

Marsha Gatling – Supervisor at Home Depot (Summer 2020)

• (281)-799-5743

Treyton Zanutto - Roommate / Informal Reference

• (832)-612-8546